Deivid William Rodrigues dos Santos

Bleicherstrasse 12 • Luzern, Switzerland • <u>Deivid.w.santos@gmail.com</u> +41 79 917 0306



SOFWARE / TEST ENGINEER

I am currently engaged on Computer Programing Analyst, however, 4 years of experience as a System Analyst in a multinational company located in Brazil. I am Highly organized, self-motivated, and diligent professional with collaborative mindset and good interpersonal relationship.

- Core Competencies -

- Software Development
- Agile Methodologies
- Database Administration

- Troubleshooter
- Positive Teamwork and Collaboration
- System Administration

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Petrolink Services ., Rio de Janeiro, Brazil *Team leader Senior System Analyst* (Jun 2015 – Nov 2016)

Responsible for managing activities related to the Software branch in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. Working directly with the Director and Sales Department.

- Databases Administration
- System Administration
- Software Improvements (Asp.net / C#)
- Test Routines
- Client Meetings
- Ultimate level Support to Operations
- Training and lead Junior System Analyst / Trainee

Petrolink Services ., Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Pleno System Analyst – Test Engineer (November 2013 – June 2015)

Monitoring, maintaining, and troubleshooting of Real-time data-streams (WITS, WITSML and XML). User Access support, Data Converters and Aggregators Support in Onshore and Offshore Rigs Ensuring proper data mapping and units of measurement of all incoming Real-time data. 2nd and 3rd level support of Real-time related issues, including server issues, connection issues, internal issues, and contractor issues. Managing Databases (SQL SERVER), providing reports based on Director / Operations Request.

- Provide improvements to the System according to meetings with clients
- Report issues
- Test Case creation / Test Execution
 - Analyzing requirements/use cases/user stories from the Product Owner.
 - Participating in preparing test plans and test scenarios.

- Preparing Test Cases for modules, integration, and system testing.
- Preparing Test Data for tests.
- Preparing Test Environment to execute the test cases.
- Analyzing the Test Cases prepared by other team members.
- Executing the Test Cases.
- Defect Tracking.
- Use existing tools and frameworks to build/script test conditions for automating tests.
- Execute test cases and publish result analysis.
- Participate in troubleshooting issues alongside other technical and operational teams.
- System Administrator

Training and Specialization on Real-Time Software done in Houston – Texas. Management Software used: JIRA

Petrolink Services ., Rio de Janeiro, Brazil *Junior System Analyst* (May 2012 – November 2013)

Monitor the data flow within the client databases on the Petrolink system.

To present data to the highest standard (to enable all authorized account holders to utilize the information).

Processing of this client data will be directed by the DTL through the tracker or similar system. Each item of client data must be processed according to the procedure.

First independent client data verification and quality control check of the distribution work, i.e. first buddy procedure.

Staying abreast of client activities, both at wellsite and onshore.

Investigating new processing techniques with bespoke packages, specially log plot software.

Providing first line customer support performed by the Operations Centre.

Monitoring of the Petrolink Infrastructure, servers and websites, reporting to GIS.

To be available for a fair share of reserve call-out duty.

Mundivox Telecomunications, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil

Intern Technical Support (November 2011 – April 2012)

Mundivox is a telecommunications operator and provider

Integrated solutions for voice services and data aimed at the corporate market.

EDUCATION & CREDENTIALS

Durham College, Ontario, Canada Computer Programming Analyst **Finishing April 2021**

Linux Academy - LPI Linux Essentials

Completed: 2016-03-28

Infnet – Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Querying Microsoft SQL Server 2012 – Microsoft Partner Infnet – Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Administering Microsoft SQL Server 2012

Infnet – Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Implementing a Data Warehouse with Microsoft SQL Server – Microsoft Partner

TreinaWeb Courses – Rio de Janeiro, Brazil Basic C# programming

TreinaWeb Courses – Rio de Janeiro, Brazil SQL Server Database Administrator

UDEMY – Online Certification Prep. Course MCSA SQL Server 2019 Database Administration [On Going]

Udemy - ISTQB Foundation Level certification training for exam **Certification Exam Scheduled to the beginning of February**

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Knowledge on the Programming languages:

WPF, Windows forms, C#, Java, C++, SQL, ASP.NET, HTML/CSS, PHP, Cobol (beginner), JavaScript

Frameworks: Visual Studio, INTELLIJ IDEA, NetBeans, Eclipse, DEV-C++

Databases: SQL Server, POSTGREE SQL, MySQL.

Operational Systems: Linux, Windows

Experienced with JIRA Management Software.

LANGUAGES

Portuguese: Mother Language

English: FluentSpanish: Basic

Deutsch: Learning - Alemania Course [On Going]

Deivid William Rodrigues dos Santos 1.14.2021